yayasanbankrakyat.com.my 2019-09-11

# Yayasan Bank Rakyat - Privacy Policy

## **Scope of Notice**

This Privacy Notice outlines how Yayasan Bank Rakyat (henceforth “YBR”) collects, uses, maintains and discloses your personal data and how Yayasan Bank Rakyat Group safeguards the personal data. In addition, myYBR release the information about the Foundation to the public, media, customers, authorities, scholars, strategic partners, Bank Rakyat members, beneficiaries and other stakeholders.

“Yayasan Bank Rakyat”, “myYBR”, “We”, “Our” or “Us” in this Privacy Notice refers to Yayasan Bank Rakyat either individually or collectively. Compliance with this policy is important both for operation reasons and to meet the Foundation’s legal and regulatory obligations. 

## **Our Privacy Commitment**

This Privacy Notice is issued to inform you of the Yayasan Bank Rakyat’s commitment to the policy of protecting at all times the confidentiality, integrity and security of the information provided by you to us as we recognise the importance of the personal information we hold about customers and the trust they place in us. Your personal data is classified as confidential and can only be disclosed by Yayasan Bank Rakyat where authorized by you, permitted by any laws, (including regulations, standards, guidelines and/or obligations) applicable to the Yayasan Bank Rakyat.

## **Your consent is important**

We only collect personal information about you that is necessary to perform our functions and activities. When you request information for our products and services, you may be required to provide Yayasan Bank Rakyat with your personal data. In doing so, you consent to its use by Yayasan Bank Rakyat in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

You have the choice, at any time, not to provide your personal data/sensitive personal data or to revoke your consent to Yayasan Bank Rakyat processing of your personal data/sensitive personal data. However, failure to provide such personal data/sensitive personal data or revocation of your consent to process personal data/sensitive personal data provided may result in Yayasan Bank Rakyat being unable to provide you with effective and continuous products and services.

## **What types of personal data do we collect?**

Personal data refers to any information that relates directly or indirectly to an individual, who is identified or identifiable from that information or from that and other information in the possession of Yayasan Bank Rakyat.

The types of personal data we collect may include, but is not limited to your name, address, other contact details, age, maiden’s name.

The personal data we collect is obligatory. Obligatory personal data are those that we require in order to allow you to join our programs. If you do not provide this information or consent to certain use of your personal information, you may not be able to join programs that we are handling or establish any business dealings with you.

## **How do we collect your personal data?**

We only obtain your personal data when you sign up to join programs that we organize in Yayasan Bank Rakyat.

## **What is the purpose of processing your personal data?**

We may process your personal data to assess your application in order to join our programs. Please note that you will not receive any marketing or promotional materials/ communication once you provide us with your personal data.

## **To whom do we disclose your personal data?**

Your personal data held by us shall be kept confidential.

## **How do we protect your data?**

The security of your personal data is our priority. Yayasan Bank Rakyat takes all physical, technical and organizational measures needed to ensure the security and confidentiality of personal data.

## **How long may we retain your personal data?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose(s) for which it was collected or to comply with legal, regulatory and internal requirements. Afterwards we will destruct or permanently delete your data.

## **Changes to this Privacy Notice**

Please note that we may update this Privacy Notice from time to time. If there are material changes to this Privacy Notice, we will notify you by posting a notice of such changes on our website or by sending you a notification directly. Do periodically review this Privacy Notice to stay informed on how we are protecting your information.

## **How can you access / correct / update your personal data?**

We are committed to ensure that the personal data we hold about you is accurate, complete, not misleading and up-to-date. If there are any changes to your personal data or if you believe that the personal data we have about you is inaccurate, incomplete, misleading or not up-to-date, please contact us so that we may take steps to update your personal data.

You have the right to access your personal data. If you would like to request access to your personal data, please contact us. We may also take steps to verify your identity before fulfilling your request for access to your personal data.

## **How may you contact us?**

If you need to contact us, you may visit us at Floor 8, Tower 1, Menara Kembar Bank Rakyat, No. 33 Jalan Rakyat 50470, Kuala Lumpur, call our direct line at **603 -26129600** , or visit us at [www.yayasanbankrakyat.com.my](http://yayasanbankrakyat.com.my/)
